SOHEIL KHANI

Email: soheil.khani22@gmail.com Phone: (647)5610150 Address: 6 Emmanuel Dr, Richmond Hill, ON, L4B 1Y4

PERSONAL STATEMENT:

Talented Mechanical engineer graduated from the University of Ottawa in Mechanical engineering (Master's degree with the overall score A), with 3 years professional experience in the manufacturing and automotive sectors. Seeking a position as a mechanical engineer in a result oriented company where acquired skills and education will be utilized towards continuous growth and advancement and also provide opportunity to learn new technologies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

CAD: AutoCAD (3 years), SOLIDWORKS (3 years), CATIA (3 years), Inventor (3 years), Pro/E

FEM analysis: (ANSYS and ABAQUS) **Programming:** Matlab, C/C ++, java

MS Office Software (Access, Excel, PowerPoint, Word, Outlook)

Windows operating system

AREA OF EXPERTISES:

- 3D modeling and engineering drawing utilizing CAD (SolidWorks and AutoCAD in particular) , Prepare Bills of materials
- In depth Knowledge of various manufacturing process (CNC machining , Die casting, forging ,welding , pressing) and materials
- Knowledge of GD&T for machining and sheet metal production
- Machinery design

EDUCATION:

Master of engineering in Mechanical engineering

University of Ottawa (2015), Ottawa, Ontario, Canada (Overall score: A)

B.SC in Mechanical engineering (Manufacturing and Production)

Central Tehran branch of AZAD University (2011), Tehran, Iran

EMPLOYMENT:

Junior Mechanical Design Engineer

SAMUEL Packaging system, Vaughan, Ontario, Canada (February 2019-July 2019)

Nature of business: Packaging & Material handling equipment supplier

- Designed and detailed mechanical components and assemblies by utilizing SolidWorks and AutoCAD for manufacturing purposes
- Liaised with the manufacturing team in construction and assembly of prototypes in the machine shop in order to confirm the feasibility of products
- Prepared manuals and technical documentation for projects

- Selection of mechanical components such as actuators, motors, fasteners, bearings, etc...
- Created BOMs using SOLIDWORKS, and AUTOCAD

Mechanical Engineer

SAIPA Corporation, Tehran, Iran (October2017- March2018)

Nature of business: Car manufacturing company

- 3D modeled mechanical parts and assemblies by using SOLIDWORKS and AutoCAD under supervision of senior mechanical engineer
- Produced engineering reports, documentation and calculations demonstrating the malfunctioning of specific designs
- Developed test procedures to ensure quality control
- Monitored manufacturing processes effectively during daily quality control/assurance
- Served as a member of the Manufacturing Engineer Group accountable for developing costeffective solutions to manufacturing production issues
- Researched on new technologies based on automotive industry

Manufacturing engineer

ARAN Company, Tehran, Iran (FEBRUARY 2011-DECEMBER 2012)

Nature of business: Designing and making standard machinery of automatic food production lines and designing food automation lines.

- Produced 3D models and detail drawings for parts and assemblies by utilizing SolidWorks and AutoCAD
- Assisted project team in project planning/budgeting, monitoring project progress and Timelines, coordinating activities, collecting/analyzing data and reviewing material selection
- Improved operating procedures through the reconfiguration of an existing plant structure from the viewpoint of process safety and operability by the use of CGU(Control Group Unit)
- Coordinated safety, maintenance and repair services schedule in order to maintain equipment and machines operational
- Analyzed the cost of materials, labor and overhead required for new or existing products and, processes(automatic cake and cookie production line), and proposed new methods and designs to reduce cost and inefficiencies

PERSONALITY TRAITS AND SKILLS:

- Quick learner and Enthusiastic to learn new skills and techniques
- Excellent time-management and organizational skills acquired by working on multiple tasks simultaneously and meeting tight deadlines
- Excellent interpersonal, leadership, teamwork and presentation skills acquired through leading various project teams
- Excellent written and verbal communication
- Ability to work with minimal supervision
- Self-starter and creative problem- solving

REFERENCES:

References are available on request